In the area around Pęgów,
people call it
a strawberry village.
This comes from fields
full of strawberries
and a special event.
It is the Strawberry Festival
organized by a local association.
The festival has
over 20 years
of tradition.
It did not take place
during the COVID time.
In 2026, it will be
the 18th edition.
It is definitely worth
planning a visit!
There are stage stars
and many attractions
for children.
There are puppet shows
and an inflatable playground.
There are also
exciting contests.
For example:
best strawberry cake
or best costume.
You can even compete
in eating strawberries
for time.
In Pęgów, strawberries are not just fruit—
they are a reason to celebrate!