Not long ago in Poland,
there lived a man
named Kornel Morawiecki.
He loved science,
freedom,
and mysteries.
By day, he taught students
how the world works.
After hours,
he did very brave things.
Did you know
some books and newspapers
were banned back then?
Kornel helped print them
in secret.
So people could learn
the truth.
The most special place
in his life
was a house nearby
called Kornelówka.
It was not
a normal house.
Kornel built it himself
from wooden railway ties.
It stood among trees,
like an adventure hut.
To buy the land,
he became… a farmer!
He learned to farm
and passed an exam,
even though he was
a scientist at heart.
Guests often came,
saying they picked mushrooms.
But they came
for something else.
Secret meetings happened here,
for a free Poland.
Kornel founded
Fighting Solidarity.
In autumn 1990,
the house burned down.
But his son rebuilt it.
Freedom lives there again.