From where you are now,
you can see the church.
It does not look
very old, right?
But the parish here
already existed
in the 17th century.
Documents say that in 1666
there was a wooden church
covered with clay.
At that time,
the Reformation happened.
It was a religious movement
that created
new Christian groups.
The number of Catholics
became much smaller.
By 1706,
the church was ruined.
By the late 1700s,
it was gone.
Today we do not know
its exact place.
But one item survived.
A stone baptismal font.
It was likely used
in the first church.
When the church disappeared,
the parish ended.
Pęgów joined
the parish in Uraz.
People walked
several kilometers
to Sunday Mass.
This lasted until 1952,
when Pęgów joined
the parish in Szewce.
Church was closer then,
because a palace
was used as a church.
But it still was
not perfect.
So in 1977,
construction began.
This was the current church.
It was a hard time
for building churches.
Work lasted until 1984.
In 1985,
the parish returned.
Since then,
it has worked independently.