The railway station building
has not been used
for many years.
But trains still stop here.
From here you can travel
to Wrocław,
or the other way
to Oborniki Śląskie
and farther
to Poznań.
This railway line
was built
over 150 years ago,
in the year 1856.
But Pęgów did not get
its station right away.
It was built
50 years later,
in 1905.
Back then, trains
were very important.
Cars were slow,
often broken,
and only rich people
could afford them.
Thanks to the railway,
Pęgów became
a trip destination
for people from Wrocław.
Several tourist routes
were created.
One led to Wilczyn
through a lovely forest.
A lot has changed
in 100 years,
but Wilczyn is still
great for trips.
There are beautiful
relaxing areas
by the water.
Walking through the forest,
you can follow
the Chestnut Avenue —
rare trees in a forest!