Historic documents say
that Pęgów has existed
since the 13th century.
But wait —
people lived here
much earlier!
Amazing finds prove it:
a stone axe
and a stone hatchet
were discovered
right here.
Scientists say
they come from
the Stone Age,
from the Neolithic period.
Imagine — this was
the same time
when pyramids were built
in ancient Egypt!
That was
4 to 6 thousand
years ago.
Amazing, right?
But this is not
the most exciting discovery!
In fields near Pęgów,
a real treasure
was found.
It was a pot
filled with
gold coins
from around
the year 1060.
The treasure weighed
half a kilogram
and had
406 coins.
Among them were coins
of Hungarian kings:
Solomon,
Stephen I,
and Béla I.
There was also a coin
of King Cnut,
the ruler of Denmark
and Britain.
There were coins
of German emperors:
Henry II
and Otto III.
The treasure was likely
linked to an old
trade route
that ran north
of Wrocław.
Why did someone bury
a pot full of gold?
We can only guess.
Maybe it was a merchant
afraid of robbers
who hid his wealth
in a safe place.
Did his plan work?
We don't know.
One thing is sure —
he never came back.