In Pęgów,
we are not afraid
of fires.
We have
experienced firefighters.
The local fire unit
was created
right after
World War II.
Back then,
war damage
was everywhere.
It was very hard
to get equipment.
Luckily,
an old horse-drawn
fire pump survived.
Thanks to it,
firefighters
began helping people.
Even with
very simple tools.
Over time,
the unit grew
stronger.
It improved
when taken over
by a state farm.
But the building
was still not great.
The fire station
was in this building.
In the video,
we see it
after renovation.
The renovation happened
in the 1990s.
In 2014,
firefighters moved
to a new,
big, modern station.
Now they leave
from there
to fight fires
and help people
where it is needed most.