This ivy-covered tree
is slowly reaching
the end of its long life.
If we move the ivy,
we can find a small sign.
It says this is a pedunculate oak
called "The End and The Beginning".
The name comes from
a colorful art project
made in 2012
by artist Łukasz Berg.
Even then, the tree no longer
looked like a proud
natural monument.
Its meaning also changed.
As art, it was meant
to show friendship,
peace, and including
everyone together.
But how did this oak
end up in the village center?
It was planted in the dark 1930s,
when this land was ruled
by Nazi Germany.
It honored victims
of World War I,
but also Nazi ideas.
Planting oaks was meant
to be a symbol of power
and long life.
They believed their empire
would last a thousand years,
like strong old oaks.
But it ended quickly.
The empire fell before
the oak even grew up.
This shows that big ideas
can fade faster
than a simple tree.