In Pęgów,
there are several
old houses.
Can you guess
which one is the oldest?
Maybe it is the palace
in the village center?
No!
The oldest house
is not grand at all.
It is actually
in very poor condition.
It fits its age
very well.
It is over 100 years old
and was built
in the 19th century.
Its walls show
how it was built.
This is called
"Prussian wall".
It is a wooden frame
filled with bricks.
Or maybe it is not
Prussian wall?
Maybe it is
a wattle and daub wall,
filled with clay
and straw instead?
What do you think?
Can you tell
the difference?
There are more houses
over 100 years old.
Look at the old shop
made of brick.
It used to be
an inn.
Also the villas
near the train station.
They show
old village wealth.
Everything was centered here,
close to the railway.
For a long time,
it was the only good link
to Wrocław.