We can see here
a partly overgrown
deep ditch.
Ditches are usually dug
to drain water.
But why would anyone
dig them in a forest?
What secret
do they hide?
These ditches stretch
for many kilometers.
They used to be
even longer.
They were dug
from the Oder River
near the village of Raków
to Trzebnica.
They were part of
a defense line
called “Bartold”.
It was meant to protect
Wrocław
from the Red Army.
These were
anti-tank trenches.
They were very deep,
so tanks could not cross.
They formed
a continuous line
that was hard to bypass.
Only road crossings
were left open.
There, concrete blocks
were placed.
In case of attack,
they could be blown up
to block the road completely.
Would this defense line
have worked?
We will never know.
The main attack
came from
a different direction.