We are in Pęgów.
It is quite an unusual
name for a village.
But even more interesting is
that in 1947
this place was called Henryków.
It was a Polish version
of the German name
Henigsdorf.
It meant
“Hennig’s village”.
Why was the name changed?
And how was it decided?
The second answer is simple.
South of Wrocław,
there is another Henryków.
Two places with the same name
caused confusion.
So a change was needed.
But how did Henryków
become Pęgów?
Officials checked
old 13th-century records.
They found a village name:
Panglouo.
Old notes described
a border stone.
It was between Machnice,
Brochocin and Pęgów.
The first two villages
still exist today.
They are quite close by.
But are they close enough
for a border stone?
What do you think?
Are we in ancient Panglouo,
or in “Hennig’s village”?