Have you heard the name
“Festung Breslau”?
It was a system
of fortifications
built around Wrocław
by the Germans
to defend against
the Red Army.
Here, where you are now,
a field airstrip was built.
It was never used
very intensively.
Its creation
has a sad history.
It was built by
the Organisation Todt,
which used forced labor
from prisoners of war
and people
from occupied areas.
The organization was founded
by Fritz Todt,
an engineer and minister
of armaments
of the Third Reich.
From 1942,
it was led
by Albert Speer.
Under their leadership,
the organization
used the lives
of conquered people
to support the war effort
of a collapsing state.
Fortunately,
those times are gone.
Now there are fields here.
With luck, you can even see
a flock of cranes.