To find this treasure
you had to walk along the historic linden alley
the trees there are over 300 years old
Do you see the cross here?
Next to it, there is a stone in which
miraculously, someone has left footprints
A legend explains how this happened
Supposedly, a man once passed through here
and cursed God
God was so angry with him
that threw a thunderbolt
which struck the man
leaving his feet imprinted on the stone
This legend was repeated
in the form of a caricature
at a time when instead of policemen
we had militiamen in our country
An officer wanted to confront God
He pulled out his service pistol
and shot twice at the image of Christ
The bullet holes are still there
but other than that
it didn't hurt God