Welcome to Kalinowice
a town whose name may come from the viburnum
However, this is not certain
As there isn't much of this plant around
On the other hand
the first historical owners of the village
were the Kalinowski family
And the name of the town may come from their surname
It was long time ago
The Kalinowski family has been gone
from Kalinowice for over 200 years
Only a few traces of their presence remain
Their graves can be found in the crypt
in the sanctuary on Saint Anne's Mountain
and in the church in nearby Kalinów
there is a monstrance funded by them
which, due to its great historical value
is not available to visitors
There is no certainty about the origin of the name Kalinowce
I'm betting on the Kalinowski family
What do you think?