We are in Dąbrowa
a pre-war farm
The object may seem inconspicuous
but history has left a dramatic mark on it
According to some, tragic events took place here
during the Silesian Uprising
A unit of scouts - insurgents
died here
and their bodies were drowned
in one of the farm wells
After the war
a unit of Hubertus' Black Wolves - Hitler's last soldiers
found shelter here
German partisans who led a terrorist fight
immediately after World War II
Here they tried to organize a secret weapons warehouse
But there is nothing to fear
the members of the organization were arrested a long time ago
and the military equipment was removed from here