Does Kalinowice have a resident who visits Africa every year?
Of course, it's our stork!
Storks are birds that fly to warm countries for the winter
They spend the coldest months in Egypt
and if they have the inclination to travel further
they can reach Uganda, Ethiopia, Nigeria, Sudan
or even South Africa
Take a look at our stork
does he look like a fan of long journeys?
There is also an interesting story behind the nest itself
It was originally located in a barn
that was destroyed by fire
However, the inhabitants of Kalinowice
were so attached to the stork
that they moved its nest to a pole
where it is located to this day