For many years
one of the biggest prides of Kalinowice
has been one of the oldest
ginkgo trees in the country
This exotic tree was probably brought here
by the von Gronow family a long time ago
Take a look at its leaves
What do they remind you of?
Have you seen them somewhere before?
The ginkgo leaf has become
the unofficial symbol of the village
and you might have seen it on
the welcome signs at the entrance to Kalinowice
Unfortunately, the last few years
have not been kind to our prized tree
It was struck by lightning
causing one of its main branches to fall off
and we don't know what will happen to it in the future
Ginkgo trees are very useful
They are used to make medicines
that can help prevent strokes
and improve memory