Back in the 19th century
the most popular food product in these region were groats
Do you like fries?
But you can't make fries from groats
Fortunately, culinary habits have been changed
by the actions of innovators promoting novelties such as potatoes.
Kalinowice, thanks to the earls von Gronow
who ruled here at that time
became the precursor of growing this vegetable
which is necessary for the production of French fries
This appetizing story is commemorated
by the potato digger seen here
The fact that the digger was manufactured
in an agricultural machinery factory in nearby Strzelce Opolskie
adds additional historical attractivity
This factory no longer exists
but in its heyday it was
the largest plant of this type
in the country
and the only one producing potato diggers