We are now in a special place.
Adults will find lots of interesting facts about Kalinowice
on the historical board here
which I helped create
For the younger ones
I invite you to spend
some unforgettable moments
at the playground across the square
Right next to us
is the Volunteer Fire Department station
so don't be surprised
if you suddenly hear a loud siren
and see a fire truck rushing out with its lights on
Years ago
a police car from the militia
could also rush out from here
This building used to be a police station and jail
The policeman could act like a sheriff
taking action with a weapon
and putting suspects behind bars