The school building you see here
is quite new
so you might be surprised
to learn that a school
has been in Kalinowice for over 100 years
The first school was on Wiejska Street
but it quickly became too small
for all the kids
who wanted to learn
The second school was built
right here in the 1930s
I actually went to this school
Here you can see me
in a picture from
the end of the school year
The picture shows
an interesting local tradition where
7th graders say goodbye
to the 8th graders
who are leaving school
Can anyone spot me in the picture?
When I finished school
there were so many students
that they needed an extra building in Kalinów
to fit everyone
About 20 years ago
the school was expanded
to look like it does now
Unfortunately, in recent years
there have been fewer children
and the authorities decided
that keeping such a big school
was too expensive
Now, only part of the building is used
and it's just a preschool